[
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of South Sudan?",
        "answer": "Juba"
    },
    {
        "question": "Juba is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "South Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "South Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What place is also known as `land nearest nowhere`?",
        "answer": "Cape Three Points"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the official language of Austria?",
        "answer": "German"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Austria?",
        "answer": "Vienna"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Swimming Hall of Fame located?",
        "answer": "Fort Lauderdale, Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Tennis Hall of Fame located?",
        "answer": "Newport, Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Track and field Hall of Fame located?",
        "answer": "Indianapolis, Indiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest landlocked county in England?",
        "answer": "Shropshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state has the most national parks?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?",
        "answer": "Cook Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tallest free-standing mountain in the world?",
        "answer": "Mount Kilimanjaro -- It is not part of a mountain range, which makes it the tallest free-standing mountain in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Seven Summits is also the highest island peak in the world?",
        "answer": "Puncak Jaya -- Also known as Carstensz Pyramid, it is located on the western half of the island of New Guinea."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the original name of Denali, the tallest mountain in North America?",
        "answer": "Denali -- The name was changed to Mt. McKinley in 1896 after then-presidential candidate William McKinley."
    },
    {
        "question": "On the `Eight Summits` list, where is the extra peak located?",
        "answer": "Australia -- Some mountaineers prefer the `Eight Summits` list, which gives Oceania an extra peak -- Mount Kosciuszko."
    },
    {
        "question": "How many of the Seven Summits are over 20,000 feet high?",
        "answer": "Three -- Everest is at 29,035 feet, followed by Aconcagua at 22,831 feet, and Denali at 20,310 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first person to climb all of the `Seven Summits`?",
        "answer": "Richard Bass -- He climbed the first six in a single year. He completed the feat by climbing Mt. Everest in 1985."
    },
    {
        "question": "What legendary European culture hero is celebrated as an icon of beer, brewing, joviality, and joie de vivre.",
        "answer": "Gambrinus -- Some imagine Gambrinus as a man who has an enormous capacity for drinking beer."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is zucchini called in the UK?",
        "answer": "Courgette -- Zucchini/courgette is a variety of cucurbit, belonging to the same family as cucumber, squash, and melon."
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. town has a replica of the Eiffel Tower topped with a cowboy hat?",
        "answer": "Paris, Texas -- Paris, Tennessee and Las Vegas, Nevada also have replicas of the Eiffel Tower, albeit, without the hat."
    },
    {
        "question": "A person from North Carolina is properly known as a what?",
        "answer": "North Carolinian"
    },
    {
        "question": "New Hampshire, New York and Massachusetts are the three states that border which state?",
        "answer": "Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yellowknife was the first city in what area of Canada?",
        "answer": "Northwestern Territories"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US states would you find Pikes Peak?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is home to the annual `All-American Soap Box Derby`?",
        "answer": "Akron, Ohio"
    },
    {
        "question": "What West Coast city was home to Jack Murphy Stadium?",
        "answer": "San Diego"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Gem State`?",
        "answer": "Idaho"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river flows between Nebraska and Iowa?",
        "answer": "Missouri River"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Potomac River empties into what bay?",
        "answer": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state shares a border with Ohio, Indiana and Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nickname the `Bluegrass State`?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "What southern city is located on the shores of Lake Pontchartrain?",
        "answer": "New Orleans"
    },
    {
        "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe river flow?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sea does the river Elbe flow into?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kigali is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Rwanda?",
        "answer": "Kigali"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Rwanda to the west?",
        "answer": "Congo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Czech Republic?",
        "answer": "Prague"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is known as the `polar bear capital of the world`?",
        "answer": "Churchill, Manitoba -- It`s fairly common to see one strolling through the Canadian town or outside one`s bedroom window at night."
    },
    {
        "question": "How did the Pacific Ocean get its name?",
        "answer": "Portuguese explorer, Ferdinand Magellan named it `Mar Pacifico`, which means `peaceful sea` in both Portuguese and Spanish."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is unique about Australia`s Fraser Island?",
        "answer": "Stretching across approximately 76 miles, Fraser Island is the largest sand island in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which mountain range can you find Australia`s tallest peak?",
        "answer": "Australian Alps -- It is covered in ski resorts and in the summer, many people hike to its tallest peak, Mount Kosciuszko."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which continent has no active volcanoes?",
        "answer": "Australia -- All of its volcanoes are dormant, including Tweed Volcano, one of the largest extinct volcanoes in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "The ancient Egyptian symbol `Ouroboros` depicts a serpent eating what?",
        "answer": "Its own tail"
    },
    {
        "question": "What word comes from the name of a hot spring in Iceland?",
        "answer": "Geyser -- The term refers to a specific geyser named Geysir, which means `the gusher` from the Old Norse `geysa` for `to gush`."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosts an annual festival of snake charmers?",
        "answer": "Italy -- Cocullo, a medieval town in the region of Abruzzo, features the Processione dei Serpari on May 1 each year."
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?",
        "answer": "Ankara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the only Portuguese-speaking Latin American country?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    }
]